Guide to the Consumer Reports. Charles Cavagnaro papers, 1965-1978 RL.11826
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports. Charles Cavagnaro papers
1965-1978
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports (Firm)
RL.11826
0.6 Linear Feet
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Charles Cavagnaro served as a Director with the U.S. Office of Consumer Affairs and later in the Department of Health, Education and Welfare. The Charles Cavagnaro papers include clippings, correspondence, reports, statements and other printed materials relating to Cavagnaro's work on consumer education and protection with the Office of Consumer Affairs and the President's Committee on Consumer Interests. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: General Files; Office of Consumer Affairs; President's Committee on Consumer Interests.
Biographical / Historical
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Charles Cavagnaro served as a Director with the U.S. Office of Consumer Affairs and later in the Department of Health, Education and Welfare. Cavagnaro also served on the Advisory Committee for Consumers Union's Center for the Study of Consumer Movements.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Consumer Reports. Charles Cavagnaro papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Consumer Reports Archives records
Consumer Reports. Colston E. Warne papers
Consumer Reports. Esther Peterson papers
Collection Overview
The Charles Cavagnaro papers include clippings, correspondence, reports, statements and other printed materials relating to Cavagnaro's work on consumer education and protection with the Office of Consumer Affairs and the President's Committee on Consumer Interests.
Consumer education; consumer protection; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; U.S. Office of Consumer Affairs; Cavagnaro, Charles
- General Files, 1965-1978; 1
  - Agency for Consumer Protection, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Consumer Advisory Committee--Stewart Lee correspondence, 1970-1976 (Box 1)
  - Consumer education--Historical materials, 1969-1975 (Box 1)
  - Consumer education--Historical materials, 1973 (Oversize-folder 1)
  - Office of Consumer Representation, 1978 (Box 1)
  - Office of the Assistant to the President for Reorganization--Frank McLaughlin comments, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Regional consumer conferences: Report to the President, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Special Assistant to the President for Consumer Affairs--Betty Furness correspondence, 1967-1969; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Special Assistant to the President for Consumer Affairs--Virginia Knauer correspondence, 1969-1975 (Box 1)
  - Special Assistant to the President for Consumer Affairs--Virginia Knauer correspondence, 1969 (Oversize-folder 1)
- Office of Consumer Affairs, 1972-1977; 2
  - Career and Educational Opportunities in the Consumer Field (John Burton), 1975 (Box 1)
  - Catch-Up Conference, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Implementing Consumer Policy in the United States (Charles Cavagnaro), 1975 (Box 1)
  - Potential Economic Benefite of Consumer Education, 1977 (Box 2)
  - Report on Funeral Services (Kathryn Eilers), 1972 (Box 2)
  - Role of the Consumer in a Changing Economy (Dennis Pirages), 1976 (Box 2)
  - Universal Product Code (UPC), 1975 (Box 2)
- President's Committee on Consumer Interests, 1965-1974; 3
  - Consumer Organization Manual draft, 1968 (Box 2)
  - Consumer programs, 1965-1967 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1974 (Box 2)
  - Summary of Activities 1964-1967 (Box 2)